

# Jesse Mbaria Mwangi

Thika, 3917-01002

🛘 703705137 | 💌 jessebaryah@gmail.com | 🎁 jeseembariah.com | 🖸 jaymbaria | 🛅 Jay | 💆 jaymbaria

A disciplined, Adaptable and motivated leather science and technology graduate, intending to continue personal development as a leather technologist. I think in terms of results and objectives. I am enthusiastic, and I work with decisiveness and conviction. I have a proactive attitude and find positive ways to stimulate and engage with people.

# **Research Project**

Did a Research project to determine the nutritional value of the tannery green fleshing for potential use in Aqua feeds formulation thus reduction of tannery solid waste. Hence replacement of fish meal with proteinaceous tannery solid waste will be the best approach to ease out solid waste disposal problem for environmentalist and also beneficial as an economic feed in aquaculture.

### **Education**

#### African Centre for Data science & Analytics (AfriCDSA)

IABAC Data Scientist Certification

• My study involves machine learning, deep learning, Al

University of Nairobi Nairobi, Kenya

**BSc Leather Science and Technology** 

Leather technology

Work Experience \_

LEATHER INDUSTRIES OF KENYA

- · Analytical techniques
- · Leather science
- Tannery Engineering
- · Chemical Engineering
- Quality assurance

Thika High School Thika, Kenya

KCSF

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE), B+

Transcribing
Online
Online
2021-Present

- I mustered improved turnaround time whereby transcripts can really speed up a video editors' workflow.
- I also acquired an improved audience comprehension. Engaging in small-scale businesses/personal development in food, groceries & beverages
- Engaging in small-scale businesses/personal development in food, groceries & beverages.

Industrial Attachee Thika

• I acquired excellent designing skills combined with mental ability and artistic finesse.

- I ensured that a proper research and quality control is at its place when testing and analysis is done in the lab and for that chemical, dye stuffs and small-scale apparatus are used.
- I acquired the knowledge of maintaining stringent quality control of the leather products throughout the process, from wet blue to crust to finished leather and all aspect of production entirely undertaken in-house.

Data analyst Thika, Kenya

GOVERNMENT OF KIAMBU COUNTY 2013–2014

- I participated in carrying out data entry for Baseline survey for farmers in Kiambu County whereby I was able to analyze the current situation of farmers' Association and cooperation in the Rural pilot villages to strengthen the functions and roles of farmers' cooperatives and association in the Disaster Risk Management.
- I acquired the basic technical concepts and data and their relevance to food assistance programmes to farmers with a focus on rural livelihood
  programming linkages to markets and strengthening their cooperatives and association.

Nairobi, Kenya

2023-Present

2016-2020

2012-2015

2019-2020

**Leadership** 

#### Kenya Association of Leather Technologist & Scientists (KALTS) Member

University of Nairobi

Nairobi, Kenya 2022

• I am a member and official of KALTS professional body

Class representative - Leather Science & Technology class of 2020

University of Nairobi 2022

University of Nairobi

• A University class representative

#### Official - Nairobi University Leather Student Association (NULSA)

University of Nairobi

2016-2017

University of Nairobi

• An offcial of NULSA, An organization within University of Nairobi

		ш	
_	NI	ш	L

**Python** 

**Excel** 

**PowerBi** 

**Powerpoint** 

Word

## Referees

Mr. Joel Mwondu
University of Nairobi)

Leather science and technology

+254717186315

• Joelmwondu@uonbi.ac.ke

• dkimaiga@uonbi.ac.ke

Mr. Dennis Kimaiga

KALTS

THE KENYA ASSOCIATION OF LEATHER TECHNOLOGIST AND SCIENTIST (KALTS)

+254715431073